In Brazil, there's a whole set of elements that have been formulated
A gente tem um conjunto de elementos no Brasil
and developed by the elite to place the black wherever they wanted.
elaborados por essa elite para colocar o negro no lugar em que eles quiseram.
We have a state governor who lives in a palace, right?
A gente tem um governador que está em um palácio.
The Bandeirantes Palace, our governor official residence.
O Palácio dos Bandeirantes.
If we take the story behind it we'll understand
Se a gente for pegar a trajetória disso, vai perceber
why the governor is in the Bandeirantes Palace
porque o governador está no Palácio dos Bandeirantes
and the blacks are in Fundação Casa, Brazil's juvenile detention center,
e os pretos estão lá na Fundação Casa.
which is pretty antagonistic if we think of a path of humanization,
Que, no processo das relações sociais de humanização, são antagônicos.
isn't it? Fundação Casa, the prisons, the female prisons...
Porque a Fundação Casa ou os presídios, os presídios femininos, as Fundações Casa,
they're places of confinement
são lugares de encaixotamento
where people are thrown in there.
em que eles são jogados lá.
And the governor is in a palace...
Aí o governador está em um palácio,
It's still like an imperial-like atmosphere, isn't it?
o que ainda nos remete a essa coisa com um ar imperial ainda.